WCDB Radio; Records ua812
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
WCDB Radio Records
1962-1986
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua812
3.33 cubic ft.
This collection contains the inactive records from campus radio station WCDB and its predecessor, WSUA. Materials include meeting minutes, policy documentation, financial records, internal and external correspondence and radio schedules.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives on 1998 November 17.
Historical Note
WSUA 640AM, the University's first student radio station, was founded in 1963. It featured music, news programs, and live broadcasts of University at Albany sporting events. In 1978, the station received an FM license from the FCC and became WCDB 90.9FM. Since its switch to FM broadcasting, the station has continued to broadcast an eclectic mix of news programs and free-format music both over the air and online.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes program schedules and logs, membership lists, correspondence files with the FCC, record companies and syndicated programming vendors, budgetary records and account books, various station constitutions, station policy handbooks and DJ training materials, internal memoranda, promotional materials, FCC licensing documentation, meeting minutes for the station's executive committee, and several 45 RPM records.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
College radio stations; Radio stations; Administrative records; Minutes (administrative records); UAlbany Student Groups; State University of New York at Albany
- Radio Council and WCEA Constitutions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- WSUA Constitution, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- WSUA Constitution, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- WSUA Constitution, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- WSUA Constitution, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- WSUA Constitution, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- WSUA Constitution, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- WSUA Constitution, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Advertising, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Advertising Council, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- IBS-WSUA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Campus Relations, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ABC-Contemporary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Training, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Michelson, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cue Sheets Rocks Capsules, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cue Sheets Rocks Capsules, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence for Radio Bumps, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "National Student Nurses Association" + "Physical Fitness" Promotional Records, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Jazz Giveaways, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Promo Copy, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- UCB-University Concert Board, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- London Wavelength, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mutual Radio Network, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Record Orders, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Speaking of Soaps Promotional Letter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Cavox Productions, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Crooked House Productions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- O'Conner, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Chuck Cecil/Swingin' Years, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- London Wavelength's FrontRow Center Program, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Interviews & Front Row Center, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Jabberwocky Radio Classics Mailer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Rock Pool Promotions, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- DJ Schedules Fall '81, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- J+L Productions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Broadcast Clearances MayFest, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "Evolution of Rock" Programs, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Intercollegiate Broadcast System Syndicated Programs, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Radio Advertising Bureau Correspondence and Mailings, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Studio Clearance List, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- DJ Training Schedule and Poster, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "Sunday Night Taped" Comedy Scripts, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Progressive Radio Network Broadcast Agreement, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Honorary Member Certificate, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Program Guides, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Inter-Office Communications, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Commercials [Campus Media], Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Current Dittos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Inter-Office Communications Out, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Master Copy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Membership Forms, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Operations Personnel, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- State Policies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Station Handbook 2nd, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Executive Comm Minutes, 1969-1997 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Current Minutes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Earth Nes Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- On-air Editorials, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- On-air Editorials, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- On-air Editorials, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Executive Minutes, 1969 June-1970 May (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Executive Minutes, 1969 June-1970 June (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Executive Minutes, 1968 June-1969 July (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Executive Minutes, 1967 June-1968 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Executive Minutes, 1966 June-1967 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Executive Minutes, 1965 June-1966 May (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Executive Minutes, 1964 June-1965 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Executive Minutes, 1963 June-1964 May (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Executive Minutes, 1970 September-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Executive Minutes, 1971 September-1972 April (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Executive Minutes, 1972 September-1973 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- FM Radio "Philosophy", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Engineering Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- SPORTS Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Secretarial Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Operations Staff, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Programming Staff, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Music Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- General Staff Spring '73, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- News Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Alpha Phi Gamma, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Equipment Inventory, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- House of Wong Advertising, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Intercourse, Public Affairs Program, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Iota Beta Sigma, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Membership, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Constitutions and Handbook For Iota Beta Sigma, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Hermes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Record Library, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Iota Beta Sigma, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Intercollegiate Broadcast System, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Inter-office Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Membership Lists, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Letters to Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Interested Fall 1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Interest Fliers, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Executive Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Members, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Atm Records, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- ABC Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Atlantic Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Bell Records (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Buddah Records, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Canyon Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Chess-Checker Records, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Columbia Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Command-Probe Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Decca Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Dunhill Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Elektra Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Epic, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Kent, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Liberty/UA, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- London, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Mainstream, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Mercury, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- MGM, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Motown, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Polydor, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- B.T. Puppy, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Scepter, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Stax, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Uni, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Vanguard, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Warner-Brothers-Seven Arts, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Miscellaneous Companies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Station Format, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
- News Department, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- News Department Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Notice to News Staff, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Election Coverage, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Press Release and Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Station Press Releases and Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Advertisements, Undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
- WSUA Handbooks and Constitutions, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Constitutions 3rd Edition, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- FCC Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- WSUA 1st Edition Handbook, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- WSUA 7th Edition Handbook, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- WSUA 4th Edition Handbook, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Administrative File, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Contracts, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Campus Center Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Marshall Garcia Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- New DJ Orientation, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Albany Student Press Open Letter on Rockpile Concert, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Executive Staff, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Master Station Memberlists, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Press Clippings, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Executive Committee Minutes Attendance, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Air Waves Magazine Mockups, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Promotional Poster, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Song Logs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Station Handbook, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Station Callsign Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- FCC Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- The State of New York Emergency Broadcast System(EBS) Operational Plan, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Roof Photographs for FCC, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- FM Licensure, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- FM Construction Plan, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Emergency Broadcast System Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 100 Watt Construction, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- DJ List, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence with other Radio Stations, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Promotions, 1972; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Frequency Check Reports, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ed Perry Associates, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Printing Officer File, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Educational FM Associates, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Program Guides, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Song Logs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence to/from Communications Commission, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Communications Commission Minutes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Eight Min Format History of WSUA, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Publicity Promotions Public Relations, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Programming, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Communications Out, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Chronicle, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Telephone Numbers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Press Card Lists, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Programming Schedule, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- SPORTS, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Office Supplies, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Log Policies, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Administrative Affairs, 1965-1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Athletic Advisory Board Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Alumni Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- List of Members, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Trophy Order Information, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- WSUA Banquet Files, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- WSUA Banquet Materials, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Banquet, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Banquet, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Campus Media Inc. Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Holmes+Mancini "Whatever Happened/ Once-a-Year Love Affairs" 45, Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Station Posters, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Station Handbook 7th Edition, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Programming Schedule, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Master Playlist, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
- DJ Schedules Requests, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Master Lists, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Feature Schedules, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Meeting Notes, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Transition to FM and Press Clippings, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- WSUA "Straight Line", 1977 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Programming Proposals, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Fountainhead(band) Promotional Materials, Undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
- "Jockey Briefs" DJ Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- LoudEAST RULES, Undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Ledger Book, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Fiscal and Budgetary Files, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- WCDB Survey, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Station Founding and 10th Anniversary Files, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Control Administration Communication, Undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Drafts of FCC FM Application, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Exhibits for FCC FM Application, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Engineering Exhibit for Transmitter Site Change, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- AP Radio Files, 1964-1978 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Correspondence Received, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Renewal 100Watts, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Executive Staff, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "Attitudes, Preferences and Behavior: The SUNY Albany Radio Survey", 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Executive Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Sponsored Events, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Administrative/Budgetary, 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- University Communication, 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- WSUA/WCDB History, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Community Leader Survey, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- News Programming Files, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- National Federation of Community Broadcasting Programs and Promotions, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Capital Cablevision Correspondence, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Schedules, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Spectrum Public Affairs Program, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Sports Programming, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Havoc Hall Program Scripts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Music Playlists and Surveys, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- ABC Radio Correspondence, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)